<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Pixleon</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/logo.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less is more</title>
      <link>/post/slim-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/slim-demo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I have reworked the demo version of Marbleous Blocks. It is a lot slimmer than the previous version, only featuring 10 puzzles. I hope this is enough to give the player a good idea of what kind of game experience to expect and whether he or she would be interested in buying the game or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new version is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pixleon/pixleon.github.io/releases/download/mb/Marbleous.Blocks.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from this I have been working on a new game mechanic that I think will have an interesting impact on the game experience, but I will present this later in another post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cover art</title>
      <link>/post/cover-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/cover-art/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have started preparing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pixleon/pixleon.github.io/releases/download/mb/Marbleous.Blocks.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Marbleous Blocks&lt;/a&gt; for early access on Steam. There are quite a few steps involved in this process. One of them being cover art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that is what I have been working on during evenings this week. Above you can see one of the images I produced. It showcases some features in the game like various marbles with different abilities, falling blocks, catapults, various &amp;ldquo;connectors&amp;rdquo; (the green symbols) etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a lot of fun working with 3D-modeling and rendering again. Last time I did it &amp;ldquo;seriously&amp;rdquo; was with 3ds Max 4 around 20 years ago - wow, time really flies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway today I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blender.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blender&lt;/a&gt;, and it has evolved tremendously since last I tried it. There are still some things that feel awkward, like multi select, but overall it allows you to do what I want, and there are a lot of possibilities for customization of the UI. The interactive path tracing they provide was of great help when trying to find the correct look for the cover art. Blender is an excellent tool for indie developers for various reasons. To begin with it is completely free of charge. On top of that there is a big community around Blender which makes it easy to find answers to questions you might stumble across when working in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another tool I used was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GIMP&lt;/a&gt; which is a free image editor that I am also quite fond of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools like this enable developers like myself to make pretty high quality stuff without spending a fortune. If Pixleon ever would become financially successful I need to look into giving back to this community of great/free tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New demo</title>
      <link>/post/new-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/new-demo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I uploaded a new version of Marbleous Blocks. This version contains bug fixes, various level editor improvements and five new puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are now a whooping 23 puzzles in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pixleon/pixleon.github.io/releases/download/mb/Marbleous.Blocks.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;demo&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not expect the final demo to contain more puzzles than this (possibly fewer) but I might tweak and rearrange puzzles depending on feedback I get from play testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating puzzles is fun and challenging. Lately I have found inspiration from shapes and patterns. For instance I might start to build a puzzle from a hearth shape or from a checker pattern. It does not always result in an interesting puzzle but usually you just need a seed of inspiration to get your mind spinning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to reach 50 puzzles before releasing the game so there is still lots of work left to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a good idea for a puzzle please send us an &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mail@pixleon.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or try to create it yourself in the demo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trailer</title>
      <link>/post/trailer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/trailer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just uploaded a short trailer for the beta version of the Marbleous Blocks. To produce the trailer I used the built-in Windows 10 Game bar capture tool along with an awesome (free) piece of software called &lt;a href=&#34;https://fxhome.com/hitfilm-express&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hitfilm Express&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/rSl9THp6nYs&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pixleon would be very happy if you would consider to try out the beta. It is free and available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pixleon/pixleon.github.io/releases/download/mb/Marbleous.Blocks.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Pixleon would be even happier if you would &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mail@pixleon.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;share your impressions&lt;/a&gt;. Is is too easy/hard? Which level was most fun? Are the controls intuitive? Please help us make this game the best it can be. Many thanks in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More levels</title>
      <link>/post/more-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/more-levels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A number of friends and colleagues have tried the game now and I have gotten some really valuable feedback. Many thanks to all of you. I have not been able to fix all the hickups yet but I will get there eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I released the beta I have not been able to work that much on the game. There are two reasons for this. First, I have started working full time at &lt;a href=&#34;https://configura.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Configura&lt;/a&gt; again. No more Tuesdays off to work on the game, at least not at this time. Secondly and more important, me and my wife got our second child - a healthy baby girl. Even though programming and game development is something I really enjoy it is nothing compared to what I get back from my family - you are the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, I have made a bit of progress since last time. There are now five new levels available in the beta that can be downloaded for free &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pixleon/pixleon.github.io/releases/download/mb/Marbleous.Blocks.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I got some feedback concerning the steep increase in difficulty and to alleviate that I have created a few more introductory levels&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next step is to create even more levels. I still have not made a trailer so that is also high on my priority list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also started to design a &amp;ldquo;directed raft&amp;rdquo; feature. It is basically a block that can carry the player/marble from one platform to another. I hope this will open up for some interesting levels. Especially in combination with the different marbles, the &amp;ldquo;catapult&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;drop&amp;rdquo; feature that is already in the game. I also aim to have triggers/button that will allow the player to change direction in which the raft moves. Time will tell if this feature is as good in practice as it is on paper. Nevertheless, trying out new things like this usually open up for new interesting ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my perspective game development is a lot about exploration of different ideas and concepts and trying out how those concepts interact with each other. This is one of the things I find particularly engaging and fun when it comes to working with interactive software such as games.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beta release</title>
      <link>/post/beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/beta-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After total silence for a few months I am happy to announce that there is a playable &amp;ldquo;early beta&amp;rdquo; version of Marbleous Blocks available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pixleon/pixleon.github.io/releases/download/mb/Marbleous.Blocks.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. At the time of writing there are 12 puzzles available but hopefully the number of puzzles will increase quite a bit before the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what have I been spending time on since December? A lot of different things actually, but here is an overview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extending the level editor with various features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimenting with different game mechanics to improve variation.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Catapults.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Falling blocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for three marbles with different abilities.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Normal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lightweight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anti-gravity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Save/Load progress.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for auto save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving the menu system.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show credits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save slots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrading C++ version along with different libs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redesigning world piece placement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding suitable game music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking over licenses for assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving first impression and robustness by:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installing C++ redistributable package if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showing a custom program icon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solving the notorious dll loading problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving hints to the player how to interact with the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworking color palette.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polishing of graphics. Shaders, 3D-models and materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating an automatic script for packaging the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugging various problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any feedback concerning the &amp;ldquo;early beta&amp;rdquo; version of Marbleous Blocks I would be very happy to hear from you. Please send me an &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mail@pixleon.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some geek stats gathered by using &lt;a href=&#34;http://cloc.sourceforge.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cloc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Languages&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;files&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;blank&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;comment&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Marbleous Blocks&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C++&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3575&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4211&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10112&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C/C++ Header&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;98&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1283&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;320&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3641&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;make&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;48&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;152&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DOS Batch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;53&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Windows Resource File&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SUM:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4931&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4549&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13959&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pixleon Engine&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C++&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;97&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3008&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3265&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6658&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C/C++ Header&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;169&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2241&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1137&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4923&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;make&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;53&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;246&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DOS Batch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;107&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SUM:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;282&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5399&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4455&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11934&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next step is to create more interesting levels along with a short trailer to showcase the game. In the meantime I hope you enjoy the beta.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level editor</title>
      <link>/post/level-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/level-editor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think it is about time I share a bit more information about the game I am working on and what I have been up to during the last couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is called Marbleous Blocks. It is a minimalistic 3D-puzzle/physics game, that consist of several small puzzles. Each puzzle is composed of a few floating platforms and the goal is to guide a marble between those platforms. In order to do so you need to carefully place Tetris-like block pieces between the floating platforms. However, in order to forge a piece, you need a blueprint for the piece and enough block energy. So, it is not just a matter of finding a valid path, you also need to think about how to spend your block energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout a puzzle there may be various useable objects that can be picked up. Some examples include blueprints, energy units and catapults. It is also possible to change the marble you are using to a different one with other properties. Initially you will just have a single marble but as you progress you will find new marble friends that will join your quest. The idea with this approach is to keep the game interesting, but also to increase the difficulty of the puzzles by having more game mechanics to combine in various ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been playing around with different ways to interact with the marble. Initially my idea was that the player would control the marble in a direct fashion by using a game pad or keyboard, but early testing proved that the interesting part of the game was to find solutions to puzzles rather than having direct control over the marble. A bonus of this design decision is that the entire game can be played just by using the mouse. I think this has the big benefit of making the game much easier to approach for non-experienced players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last couple of weeks I have been working on a level editor. The reason is to simplify puzzle creation but also give future players a way to challenge their creativity. My initial approach was to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lua.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lua&lt;/a&gt; for level creation but even though that allowed for fast iteration it is not as straight forward and playful as dragging or &amp;ldquo;painting&amp;rdquo; out various game objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how did it go? Overall, I think it went pretty good. I have not been able to finish all the tasks related to the level editor yet, but I think I have a good scalable solution now. Using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ocornut/imgui&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dear IMGUI&lt;/a&gt; was a good decision, at least it seems like a good choice so far. There are plenty of examples available and the API is clean and easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is next? Well, currently I am looking into how to create interesting levels of varying difficulty. I realize that it will take lots of play testing to find the right balance. It is so easy to assume certain things when you design puzzles and these assumptions may prove to be wrong. I am also trying to figure out what game mechanics that will give the game the variation needed to keep players interested. I think am on a good path but I will let future play testing be the judge of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is it for this time. Hopefully I can share some more footage from the game and editor in the upcoming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world</title>
      <link>/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello fellow reader and welcome to my site where I will be sharing information about myself and my indie game adventure. Before I tell you a bit more about Pixleon AB I think it is appropriate to give a short introduction of who I am.
My name is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jimmiewest.se/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jimmie West&lt;/a&gt;, a 35 years old Swedish family man and software developer. It is very important to me to put my family first. If they feel well, I feel well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the last 10+ years I have been working at an awesome company called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.configura.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Configura&lt;/a&gt;. Configura’s vision is to become the global leader for developing software used to design spaces. It’s been a fun and at times challenging but rewarding journey and I am happy that I got this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like for many other people my age, my fascination for games started with the NES. While playing most of NES games you really needed to focus, otherwise you would “die” and eventually need to restart the game from the beginning. There was “lots at stake”. I think this formed me as a person quite a bit. For instance, I could spend months just trying to figure out how to make jump with my skateboard, but when I finally figured it out, I felt invincible. In this way I learned that hard work and staying focused usually pays off. My greatest talent is my ability to stay focused and goal oriented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why do I want to make games? To become rich and famous? No, not really. The primary driving force for me is the creative freedom and possibility to express and challenge myself through this art form. I refer to it as art rather than engineering even though having engineering skills obviously help with some aspects of game development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the upcoming six months I will spend one workday a week developing a &lt;a href=&#34;http://pixleon.com/project/marbleous-blocks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;puzzle game&lt;/a&gt; for PC. At this point the scope seems to be within reach but there is usually a lot of unforeseen events along the road of completing something, but that is also one of the fun parts. In order to be able to work on this from home and still have my son at kindergarten I had to create a company – Pixleon AB. Pixleon is a play on words, pixel and aeon (a long period of time). Pixels represent something creative and fun to me, so it was natural to have something related to that. It was also important to try to find a somewhat short name that is easy to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I hope you have a better idea of who I am and what motivates me. In the upcoming posts I will try to give you more information about the game I am making, the technology behind it and the ideas that go through my head while developing it. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
